<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ergo</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/</link><description>Recent content on Ergo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ergoplatform.org/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ZeroJoin: Combining ZeroCoin and CoinJoin (Alexander Chepurnoy and Amitabh Saxena)</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_05_15/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_05_15/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo update, 14 May 2020: New exchange, wallet and first mining pool with collaterals!</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_05_14_updates/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_05_14_updates/</guid><description>We have three great new developments to announce to the Ergo community, all of which will boost our user base and decentralisation!
We have not just one but three outstanding developments for the Ergo ecosystem to announce! Together, these will make it easier than ever before to acquire, trade, store and spend ERG – and will open up a huge new potential community of users, developers and hodlers.
Coinsbit listing and airdrop Firstly, ERG has been listed on Coinsbit: a major trading platform that enables fiat deposits and withdrawals via debit and credit card.</description></item><item><title>Ergo update, 14 May 2020: New exchange, wallet and first mining pool with collaterals!</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_05_14/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_05_14/</guid><description/></item><item><title>"Team" page is replaced with "Hall of Fame"</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_05_13/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_05_13/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo ($ERG) is listed on Coinsbit Exchange</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_05_13_2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_05_13_2/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo joins BPSAA thinktank</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_05_13_3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_05_13_3/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo Platform Reference Client 3.2.3 released</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_05_12/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_05_12/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Building Ergo: Lite full nodes</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_05_08_lite_full_nodes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_05_08_lite_full_nodes/</guid><description>Ergo allows any user to run a full node with low resources – meaning you can help maintain the network with a device as simple as a Raspberry Pi.
In a previous post, we looked at Ergo’s SPV mode, which allows for secure, efficient mobile clients. This enables users to make transactions using almost any device.
At the other end of the scale, you might want to run a full node.</description></item><item><title>Building Ergo: Lite full nodes</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_05_08/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_05_08/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Introduction to stablecoins</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_05_05_stablecoins/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_05_05_stablecoins/</guid><description>Stablecoins are a major use case for DeFi but come in various different forms. The stablecoin space is still relatively young and underserved – but that’s changing fast.
Stablecoins are one of the most important and popular DeFi products, enabling users to hedge and store value on the blockchain, without having to use exchanges or other centralised providers.
As a smart contracts and DeFi platform, Ergo is well suited for building all kinds of dApps, including stablecoins.</description></item><item><title>Building Ergo: SPV security</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_05_1_spv_security/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_05_1_spv_security/</guid><description>There’s often a tension in the crypto world between security and convenience. That trade-off is unacceptable if we want these technologies to be widely used. Here’s how Ergo addresses one common and very important issue.
We all know that the most secure way to use Bitcoin, or any crypto, is to download a copy of the blockchain and run a full node yourself. That way, every time you or anyone else makes a transaction, your client checks the blockchain to ensure it’s valid.</description></item><item><title>Building Ergo: SPV security</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_05_01/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_05_01/</guid><description/></item><item><title>FlowCards: A Declarative Framework for Development of Ergo dApps</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_29_flow_cards/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_29_flow_cards/</guid><description>With thanks to Robert Kornacki for polishing of the draft.
Introduction ErgoScript is the smart contract language used by the Ergo blockchain. While it has concise syntax adopted from Scala/Kotlin, it still may seem confusing at first because conceptually ErgoScript is quite different compared to conventional languages which we all know and love. This is because Ergo is a UTXO based blockchain, whereas smart contracts are traditionally associated with account based systems like Ethereum.</description></item><item><title>FlowCards: A Declarative Framework for Development of Ergo dApps</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_04_29/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_04_29/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Building Ergo: Atomic Swaps</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_24_atomic_swaps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_24_atomic_swaps/</guid><description>Because a blockchain is a siloed, self-contained system by design, interacting with other blockchain protocols is challenging. Atomic Swaps enable cross-chain exchange of digital assets, avoiding the need for centralised exchanges.
Blockchains are excellent at decentralised value transfer within their own domains. That is, you can send BTC to any Bitcoin address securely and easily, and you can send LTC to any Litecoin address securely and easily too.
But because blockchains are based on consensus between miners, they are not designed to interface with other blockchains.</description></item><item><title>Building Ergo: Atomic Swaps</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_04_24/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_04_24/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Building Ergo: Oracles</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_04_building_ergo_oracles/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_04_building_ergo_oracles/</guid><description>Blockchains are siloed systems that can only reference their own data, established by consensus. Oracles are the solution to the problem of working with external information, which is vital for many everyday use cases.
Blockchains are intentionally self-contained. They reference information only recorded within their immediate ecosystem, that has been agreed upon by a majority of miners. Since the whole point of a blockchain, based on consensus, is that there are no sources of centralisation or single points of failure, that poses a problem.</description></item><item><title>Building Ergo: Oracles</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_04_23/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_04_23/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Building Ergo: Storage rent</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_21_ergo_positioning/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_21_ergo_positioning/</guid><description>We’ve designed Ergo with long-term economic sustainability in mind, and storage rent is one of the ways we’re ensuring miners stay profitable well into the future. One community member, Robert, describes this function as ‘on-chain garbage collection’ that reduces the problem of blockchain bloat – and even makes it profitable.
The 2020 block reward reduction will probably be the most important halving Bitcoin ever experiences. This is the point where the narrative of programmatic scarcity and digital gold will truly be proven, in the context of the sharpest economic downturn in living memory.</description></item><item><title>Building Ergo: Storage rent</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_04_21/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_04_21/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo use case: Local Exchange Trading System (LETS)</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_04_03_1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_04_03_1/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo use case: ‘hot potato’ monetary policy</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_04_03/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_04_03/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo use case: Local Exchange Trading System (LETS)</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_02_use_cases/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_02_use_cases/</guid><description>The need to reform the global financial system has been clear since the last crisis in 2008. Now, COVID-19 has forced our hands. We cannot delay, and the best way to start is from the grassroots.
As lockdowns across the world effectively shut down whole sectors and a large part of the economy, we are entering a new era at breakneck pace. Central banks are taking unprecedented action in the form of money printing but, just like last time around, they will almost certainly fail at the ‘last mile’ (intentionally or otherwise): while their efforts will benefit the financial sector and the wealthy, the funds will not reach those small businesses and individuals who need them the most.</description></item><item><title>Ergo use case: ‘hot potato’ monetary policy</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_02_use_hot_potato/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_02_use_hot_potato/</guid><description>As the next financial crisis takes hold, it’s clear that conventional monetary policy is at its limit. Smart contract platforms like Ergo enable more innovative, targeted implementations of economic stimulation that the conventional banking sector cannot achieve.
Conventional monetary policy is a hammer. It works as far as it goes, but if all you have is a hammer then every problem starts to look like a nail.
When the Global Financial Crisis hit over a decade ago, central banks did what they were used to doing.</description></item><item><title>Ergo use cases: safe, simple financial contracts</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_29_ergo_use/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_29_ergo_use/</guid><description>Ergo enables new models of financial interaction, underpinned by smart contracts built on flexible and powerful Sigma protocols but easily accessible to developers.
One of the most exciting things about blockchain is the possibility of making digital agreements without any trusted intermediaries. In the simplest use case, pioneered by Bitcoin, Alice can send a payment directly to Bob, wherever the two of them are located around the world, with no bank or any trusted third party needed.</description></item><item><title>Ergo Mainnet 3.2.2 released</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_03_24/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_03_24/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Introducing Σ3 - ErgoMixer</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_03_23/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_03_23/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Building Ergo: Sigma protocols</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_16_ergo_sigma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_16_ergo_sigma/</guid><description>Ergo’s smart contracts and DeFi functionality are built on Sigma protocols – a powerful, flexible class of zero-knowledge proofs. Find out more about why they’re so important, and how they put Ergo head and shoulders above the competition.
Cryptography is a fascinating area, and one of the most exciting and intriguing concepts it offers are zero-knowledge proofs. In simple terms, a zero-knowledge proof allows someone to prove they know the solution to a problem without actually revealing the solution itself.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Σ3 – ErgoMixer</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_20_ergo_mixer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_20_ergo_mixer/</guid><description>The project uses Ergo’s Sigma protocols to enable efficient, trustless mixing of funds, enabling a high degree of privacy while ensuring security is not compromised.
ErgoMixer command-line demo tool along with detailed technical description can be found at https://github.com/anon92048/ergo-mixer-demo .
Ergo’s Sigma protocols can be used to create many interesting and exciting DeFi use cases, with greater simplicity, efficiency and security than other smart contract platforms offer. Created by one of Ergo’s community members @anon92408, Σ3 (‘Sigma Three’) is a powerful mixer that works by pooling funds and enabling participants to spend them without anyone knowing who made the transactions.</description></item><item><title>Building Ergo: UTXO vs Account</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_03_building_utxo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_03_building_utxo/</guid><description>Ergo takes the most secure and best-established features of Bitcoin and implements advanced new cryptographic features on its rock-solid foundations. This series explores the choices we have made in creating Ergo, with the first article unpacking the advantages of the UTXO model.
When you’re dealing with financial value, you cannot afford to take chances. Every architecture decision in a cryptocurrency platform has implications. While there are different ways to solve the same problem, some solutions are better tested and more reliable than others.</description></item><item><title>Building Ergo: UTXO vs Account</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_03_03/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_03_03/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo Platform Ecosystem Digest - February 2020</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_03_digest/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_03_digest/</guid><description>Ergo Platform Roadmap for 2020 has been released, the plan is minimum and very realistic https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_02_02/
Miners tested raising computational cost limit per block via voting with success
&amp;ldquo;Bypassing Non-Outsourceable Proof-of-Work Schemes Using Collateralized Smart Contracts&amp;rdquo; https://ia.cr/2020/044 was presented by Alex Chepurnoy at WTSC workshop associated with Financial Cryptography and Data Security 2020 in Malaysia
Few AMA sessions have been held with the Ergo team by Probit, ViteXExchange, and CryptoDaku.</description></item><item><title>Coinbarn, a simple wallet for Ergo has been published in Chrome store</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_02_26/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_02_26/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo Mainnet 3.2.1 released</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_02_19/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_02_19/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Welcome to Smart Money</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_02_12_welcome_to_smart_money/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_02_12_welcome_to_smart_money/</guid><description>It’s the smartest crypto you’ve never heard of. Ergo takes the best of Bitcoin and integrates Sigma protocols so powerful they make Ethereum look like it would lose a game of chess against your cat. If you’re tired of spin and hype over solid tech, Ergo will remind you that in crypto, it’s always been fashionable to be intelligent. Bright is the new black, people, and Ergo is set to dazzle you.</description></item><item><title>Ergo Platform Ecosystem Digest</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_02_04/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_02_04/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo Platform Ecosystem Digest - January 2020</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_02_04_january_digest/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_02_04_january_digest/</guid><description>Ergo Foundation has been established (https://ergoplatform.org/en/foundation/)
Security audit of most critical parts of the reference protocol client is done, report is available (https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_01_12_security_audit/)
New paper is out, &amp;ldquo;Bypassing Non-Outsourceable Proof-of-Work Schemes Using Collateralized Smart Contracts&amp;rdquo; (https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/044.pdf). This paper describes how to build a pool for Ergo based on smart contracts with collaterals.
Public Discord server has been created (https://discordapp.com/invite/gYrVrjS), please join!
Ergo Platform reference protocol client 3.</description></item><item><title>Ergo Platform Roadmap for 2020</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_02_02/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_02_02/</guid><description>Ergo community made a lot in 2019: Very stressful but successful mainnet launch A lot of updates for Ergo protocol reference client to improve its stability and enhance functionality. Wallets: Magnum, CoinBarn (coming to ChromeStore, binaries available), UI panel in the node First applications, in form of command-line scripts, so not for regular users yet: a tool for crowdfunding campaigns, Ergo Notary, Ergo Oracle. Few Ergo improvement proposals, already implemented!</description></item><item><title>Ergo Platform Roadmap for 2020</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_02_02/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_02_02/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo Platform Discord Server has been created</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_01_23/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_01_23/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bypassing Non-Outsourceable Proof-of-Work Schemes Using Collateralized Smart Contracts</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_01_17/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_01_17/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Introducing the Ergo Foundation, a community-driven entity</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_01_17_2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_01_17_2/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Security Audit (by Jean Philippe Aumasson)</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_01_12_security_audit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_01_12_security_audit/</guid><description>We would like to announce that Ergo has successfully passed security audit of certain (most critical) parts of the code. This time the audit was done by Jean-Philipee Aumasson (aka veorq, https://aumasson.jp/ ).
The detailed report is below. Nothing critical is found. Comments on issues found:
On wallet password, we'll provide a recommendation in next versions of the protocol client. Not sure hard enforcement on password will take place, but we'll do more consultations on this.</description></item><item><title>Security Audit (by Jean Philippe Aumasson)</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_01_12/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_01_12/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_01_08/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_01_08/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo Mainnet 3.2.0 released</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_01_07/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_01_07/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Coinbarn wallet now has its desktop version</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_01_04/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_01_04/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Make Your Own Ergo Wallet: Managing Ergo Coins with ErgoTool</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_01_04_2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2020_01_04_2/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Make Your Own Ergo Wallet: Managing Ergo Coins with ErgoTool</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_12_31_ergo_tool/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_12_31_ergo_tool/</guid><description>Introduction ErgoTool is a command line interface (CLI) for Ergo blockchain. You can use ErgoTool without running your own Ergo node. Even though running a node is the most secure way to communicate with the Ergo blockchain network, ErgoTool however, aims to provide more foundational tools at your disposal. Surely, you still can use it with your own running node.
In this post we will walk through simple steps to generate a mnemonic phrase, create a local secret storage and use it to send ERGs between addresses, all with the help of ErgoTool commands.</description></item><item><title>Mining Ergo for Fun and Profit</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_12_22_mining_for_fun/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_12_22_mining_for_fun/</guid><description>Ergo GPU Mining This article will help you start mining Ergo using a GPU.
Ergo mining is based on Autolykos, a Proof-of-Work algorithm designed to be ASIC and pool resistant. Miners have to perform memory-hard computations~(at least 4 GB memory is needed, but the current most efficient implementation utilizes between 8 GB of vRAM) that makes Ergo friendly for GPU mining. In addition, Autolykos requires access to private keys, thereby preventing mining pool formation.</description></item><item><title>ErgoTool: A Command Line Interface for Ergo blockchain</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_12_24/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_12_24/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Universal dApp Interface &amp; Package Standard</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_12_24_2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_12_24_2/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Early description of Ergo contractual approach</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_12_23/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_12_23/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo is using highly efficient AVL+ tree</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_12_23_2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_12_23_2/</guid><description/></item><item><title>New tutorial: 'Mining Ergo for Fun and Profit'</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_12_22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_12_22/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo Mainnet 3.1.5 released</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_12_19/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_12_19/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Ergo Cast: Understanding Ergo One Episode At A Time</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_12_16_podcast/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_12_16_podcast/</guid><description>Since the launch of the Ergo mainnet half a year ago, there has been an incredible amount of development and progress in the Ergo ecosystem. Auction smart contracts, crowdfunding, zero interest loans, privacy preserving protocols, and much more. Every week or two there's some truly novel idea or development put out, however if you're just an average blockchain enthusiast it's likely you haven't heard too much.
Why is that? The reason is that the Ergo ecosystem is making incredible strides forward in the technology side of things, however there is a distinct lack of content to consume for the average user who is interested.</description></item><item><title>A New Quest for Decentralization</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_12_12/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_12_12/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A New Quest for Decentralization, Part I: Technical Aspects</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_12_12_new_quest/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_12_12_new_quest/</guid><description>While most active conversations today in the space are about wider adoption of the blockchain technology (which often means selling out to the Wall St.) and competition with systems like Visa and Mastercard (which often means giving up with decentralization or introducing unclear security assumptions in the name of efficiency), there is the obvious need to revisit the roots of the cryptocurrency movement, which are mostly about decentralization. Many questions to be answered in clear here.</description></item><item><title>Ergo Mainnet 3.1.4 released</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_12_04_2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_12_04_2/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Typescript library for Ergo with the support of custom tokens and complex transactions</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_12_04_1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_12_04_1/</guid><description/></item><item><title>5 Ways Ergo Application Development Is Changed Forever Thanks To Appkit</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_12_03_top5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_12_03_top5/</guid><description>With thanks to Robert Kornacki and Denys Zadorozhnyi.
Ergo Appkit is a library for polyglot development of Ergo Applications based on GraalVM. GraalVM has many great use cases. Expanding on that, in this article we will go through some of the Appkit features inherited from GraalVM and take you step-by-step in learning how to take advantage of them.
0. Example Scenario 1. Java Ergo App Development 2. Low-footprint, Fast-startup Ergo Applications 3.</description></item><item><title>5 Ways Ergo Application Development Is Changed Forever Thanks To Appkit and GraalVM</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_12_03_2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_12_03_2/</guid><description/></item><item><title>How to set up and configure a full Ergo node</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_12_03_1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_12_03_1/</guid><description/></item><item><title>How to set up and configure a full Ergo node</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_12_02_how_to_setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_12_02_how_to_setup/</guid><description>This tutorial explains how to install and run a full Ergo node. It does not cover mining.
Node security There are a few important aspects of node usage that your wallet and money's safety depends on:
An Ergo node requires storing security-critical parameters in the configuration file. You should never make this file public. An Ergo node provides a REST API for interacting with the built-in wallet. Sensitive API methods require a security token, which should never be sent over untrusted channels.</description></item><item><title>ERGO ($ERG) is listed on Probit Exchange</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_10_30/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_10_30/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo Mainnet 3.1.3 released</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_10_29/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_10_29/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo Mainnet 3.1.2 released</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_10_14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_10_14/</guid><description/></item><item><title>ERGO ($ERG) is listed on HOTBIT Exchange</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_10_08_hotbit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_10_08_hotbit/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo Mainnet 3.1.1 released</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_10_08/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_10_08/</guid><description/></item><item><title>BISQ has officially added ERG</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_09_16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_09_16/</guid><description/></item><item><title>ERGO ($ERG) is listed on P2PB2B Exchange</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_09_14/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_09_14/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo and crowdfunding</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_09_06_crowdfund/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_09_06_crowdfund/</guid><description>What is Crowdfunding? Crowdfunding is a way of raising capital through the collective efforts of individuals. The campaigns are mostly started via the world wide web and allow projects and businesses to be funded by raising small amounts of money from a large number of people. One of the best known examples for successful crowdfunding startups is Oculus Rift, a virtual reality headset. The company Oculus VR initiated its campaign in 2012 and was only two years later acquired by Facebook for $2 billion total.</description></item><item><title>Ergo will be listed on Hotbit exchange</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_09_06/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_09_06/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo Mainnet 3.1.0 released</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_08_27/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_08_27/</guid><description/></item><item><title>ERGO ($ERG) is listed on Vgate Exchange</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_08_20_1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_08_20_1/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo Mainnet 3.0.7 released</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_08_20/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_08_20/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mining ERGO on AMD Cards</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_08_07_amd/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_08_07_amd/</guid><description>This tutorial will provide you with the information needed to get your AMD cards mining ERGO on either Windows or Linux.
Developer MH Samadani published his AMD Miner just three days after the official launch and is continuously updating it since. To keep track of his updates you can join the Ergo Mining Telegram Channel and search for #amdminer. You can download and look into the miner here.
The code is based on OpenCL and completely open source.</description></item><item><title>Ergo Mainnet 3.0.6 released</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_08_06/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_08_06/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo Mainnet 3.0.5 released</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_07_30/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_07_30/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo Addresses</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_07_24_ergo_address/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_07_24_ergo_address/</guid><description>In today's article, we will have a closer look into the Ergo address formatting. In addition to that we are going to explain how they work specifically as well as what makes them preferable to other types of blockchain addresses.
Let's start at the very beginning.
The moment you install any cryptocurrency wallet you automatically create an address with it. Very loosely speaking you can compare a wallet to a traditional bank account and an address to the matching account number.</description></item><item><title>Ergo Mainnet 3.0.4 released</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_07_19/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_07_19/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo Mainnet 3.0.3 released</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_07_18/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_07_18/</guid><description/></item><item><title>ERG is available in Magnum Wallet</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_07_11/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_07_11/</guid><description/></item><item><title>After-Launch Thoughts and Ergo Roadmap</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_07_09_after_launch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_07_09_after_launch/</guid><description>Firstly, we would like to thank many enthusiasts, developers, miners, other folks, and our families for measureless help with Ergo development and launching. The launch finishes a few years period of initial research and development by the Team, and also starts a new epoch, where the core technology is mostly set in stone and gradual improvements in protocol implementations and infrastructure projects become the main focus.
The current core Ergo Core Team remains fully committed to the project (at least, while the Foundation Treasury enables that).</description></item><item><title>After-Launch Thoughts and Ergo Roadmap</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_07_09/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_07_09/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo Mainnet 3.0.2 released</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_07_04/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_07_04/</guid><description/></item><item><title>ERGO ($ERG) is listed on Tidex Exchange</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_07_02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 11:08:33 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_07_02/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo Withdrawal</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_07_03_mining_withdrawal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_07_03_mining_withdrawal/</guid><description>Spending mining reward This text is to help miners to withdraw funds mined.
A lot of folks launched a node and also a miner, with pubkeyHex from the miner embedded in the node config. Now information on how to recognize the coins mined and withdraw them to another address.
On keys. A miner can see a lot of keys in different formats.
First, mining software and also mining support in the node (namely, ergo.</description></item><item><title>Ergo Withdrawal Instructions</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_07_03/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_07_03/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo mainnet is launched</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_07_01_1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 11:06:02 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_07_01_1/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo explorer released</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_07_01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_07_01/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo Mainnet 3.0.1 released</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_07_01_2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_07_01_2/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo will be listed on P2PB2B exchange</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_06_28_2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_06_28_2/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Joining the Ergo main network at the very beginning</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_06_28_mainnet-bootstrap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_06_28_mainnet-bootstrap/</guid><description>Joining the Ergo main network at the very beginning In order to join the network at its very beginning and compete to mine the genesis block, you need to follow the steps described below. If you're not going to participate in Ergo mining and just want to set up a full node, you need to follow steps 3 and 5.
Preparations 1. Build mining software Check the guide first.
Build a miner according to its readme instruction (for Ubuntu) or using Windows manual.</description></item><item><title>Joining the Ergo main network at the very beginning</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_06_28_3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_06_28_3/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Testnet 2.2.0 released</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-06-27/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-06-27/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mainnet launch - Monday, July 1, 10:00 AM UTC</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-06_26/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-06_26/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo Mining Telegram group is now open</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-06-24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-06-24/</guid><description/></item><item><title>EFYT (Ergo First Year Token) is listed on Tidex Exchange</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_06_1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_06_1/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mainnet launch postponed</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_06_13_2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_06_13_2/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Bad Crypto Podcast featuring Ergo</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_06_13/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_06_13/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Testnet 2.1.2 released</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_06_12/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_06_12/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Interview with Ergo, a platform who's building the framework for contractual money</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_06_11/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_06_11/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Agreement with SWFT Blockchain</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_06_05/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019_06_05/</guid><description/></item><item><title>New Bitcointalk thread</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-06-05-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-06-05-1/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Testnet 2.1.0 released</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-06-05-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-06-05-2/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Wallet documentation</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_06_04_wallet-documentation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_06_04_wallet-documentation/</guid><description>An Ergo node provides a built-in wallet for storing private keys and signing transactions. The following describes how to set up and protect your Ergo wallet.
The wallet uses the BIP39 standard to generate a seed from a mnemonic sentence, which is then used to generate the private keys according to the BIP32 standard (Hierarchical Deterministic Wallets). You can use your own mnemonic sentence composed of the words from one of these wordists if you want to.</description></item><item><title>Ergo whitepaper(Chinese)</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-06-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-06-03/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Trustless Local Exchange Trading System on top of Ergo</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-05-30/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-05-30/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Trustless Local Exchange Trading System</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_05_29-exchange/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 18:21:23 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_05_29-exchange/</guid><description>A Local Exchange Trading System (LETS) is aimed at developing local economy and is usually used by people of a locality in the vicinity of each other. For a brief overview of LETS see this link, which also describes an ErgoScript implementation of a committee managed LETS. We call such a system a managed or permissioned, since it depends on a committee of trusted members to enroll new members into the LETS.</description></item><item><title>The Ergo Emission Schedule</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_05_20-curve/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 15:05:06 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_05_20-curve/</guid><description>Overview Ergo’s native token is called Erg and its emission schedule may be of keen interest to users and miners of the platform. Ergs also have some unique characteristics which are highlighted in this post. Most basically and leaving out technical details, Ergo has a strictly limited supply, an 8‐year emission schedule and a declining rate of emission over these 8 years. All tokens are mined through an original Asic and Pool‐resistant Proof‐of‐Work (“PoW”) algorithm called Autolykos.</description></item><item><title>The Ergo Emission Schedule</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-05-20/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-05-20/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Testnet 2.0.5 released</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-05-17/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-05-17/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo whitepaper</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-05-15-whitepaper/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-05-15-whitepaper/</guid><description/></item><item><title>How to mine Ergo on Windows(x64)</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_05_07_mining/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_05_07_mining/</guid><description>Step 1: Tools Visual Studio
Choose free community version, you will need to select desktop development with C++ package during install.
CUDA toolkit Choose your system version, install with default options, it will update your graphics driver to a compatible version.
Curl
Generic version without SSL, binary won`t work. Choose generic source, zip and click on show mirrors. Download and unpack.
OpenSSL 1.0.2
Download and install, select the OpenSSL binaries (/bin) directory during install.</description></item><item><title>Release postponed</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-05-07-release/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-05-07-release/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ergo teaser</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-04-24-teaser/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-04-24-teaser/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Local Exchange Trading System On Top Of Ergo</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_04_22-lets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_04_22-lets/</guid><description>A local exchange trading system (LETS) is a local mutual credit association which members are allowed to create common credit money individually, with all the deals in the system written into a common ledger. As an example, assume that Alice with zero balance is willing to buy a liter of raw milk from Bob. First, they agree on a price, for example, assume that the price is about 2 Euro (as Alice and Bob are living in Ireland).</description></item><item><title>An ICO Example On Top Of Ergo</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_04_10-ico-example/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_04_10-ico-example/</guid><description>This article describes a full featured ICO (Initial Coin Offering) implemented in ErgoScript. The example covers several important and novel features of the Ergo Platform and shows how it can support complex contracts with tiny amount of code.
Part 1. Preliminaries An important design decision in a cryptocurrency protocol is specifying what a spending transaction actually spends. There are two possibilities here. The first a UTXO-based model, as in Bitcoin, where a transaction spends one-time asset containers (called as &amp;lsquo;coins&amp;rsquo; or UTXOs in Bitcoin) and creates new ones.</description></item><item><title>Ergo mining tutorial</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-04-03-ergo-mining-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-04-03-ergo-mining-tutorial/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Testnet 2.0.3 released</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-04-02-testnet-2.0.3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-04-02-testnet-2.0.3/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Q&amp;A session transcript. Mainnet launch is planned for May 26</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-03-19/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-03-19/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Q&amp;A with Alex Chepurnoy and Dmitry Meshkov</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_03_19-qa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_03_19-qa/</guid><description>First, we have a major announcement - Ergo mainnet launch is planned for May 26 if no security vulnerabilities will be found during audit process!
What are the vision about scaling and adoption? About scaling, the main approach is to avoid bloat without compromising functionality. E.g. persistent updateable storage is possible, with updates to be checked by a blockchain contract, but only digest of authenticated data structure (and some additional bytes, less than 40 bytes anyway) are stored in the UTXO set dependless on data set size.</description></item><item><title>How to set up and configure full Ergo node</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-03-17-how-to-set-up-full-node/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-03-17-how-to-set-up-full-node/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Testnet 2.0 is live! Smart contracts language updated</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-03-14/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-03-14/</guid><description/></item><item><title>ErgoScript, a Cryptocurrency Scripting Language Supporting Noninteractive Zero-Knowledge Proofs</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-03-12/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/news/2019-03-12/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Smart Contracts for the People</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2018_10_19-smart-contracts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2018_10_19-smart-contracts/</guid><description>A lot of blockchain-related news these days are saying us that a bank X or a corporation Y is going to use a &amp;ldquo;blockchain&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;reduce costs&amp;rdquo;. Basically it means that just another buzzword is considered by big banksters as just another tool to extract value from everywhere in a more efficient way, and also to save on cutting job positions.
While I am avoiding to say anything about &amp;ldquo;Satoshi's vision&amp;rdquo; (nothing but speculations could be dug there after his exodus), a broad view I witnessed in the early years around online forums users is that a cryptocurrency should provide tools to enrich the ordinary people behind their small businesses providing no much above making ends meet, not depersonalized big financial capital.</description></item><item><title>Frontend developer</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/careers/frontend/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/careers/frontend/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>