<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Building Ergo on Ergo</title>
    <link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/tags/building-ergo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Building Ergo on Ergo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ergoplatform.org/en/tags/building-ergo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Ergo: Atomic Swaps</title>
      <link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_24_atomic_swaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_24_atomic_swaps/</guid>
      <description>Because a blockchain is a siloed, self-contained system by design, interacting with other blockchain protocols is challenging. Atomic Swaps enable cross-chain exchange of digital assets, avoiding the need for centralised exchanges.
Blockchains are excellent at decentralised value transfer within their own domains. That is, you can send BTC to any Bitcoin address securely and easily, and you can send LTC to any Litecoin address securely and easily too.
But because blockchains are based on consensus between miners, they are not designed to interface with other blockchains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Ergo: Oracles</title>
      <link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_04_building_ergo_oracles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_04_building_ergo_oracles/</guid>
      <description>Blockchains are siloed systems that can only reference their own data, established by consensus. Oracles are the solution to the problem of working with external information, which is vital for many everyday use cases.
Blockchains are intentionally self-contained. They reference information only recorded within their immediate ecosystem, that has been agreed upon by a majority of miners. Since the whole point of a blockchain, based on consensus, is that there are no sources of centralisation or single points of failure, that poses a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Ergo: Storage rent</title>
      <link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_21_ergo_positioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_21_ergo_positioning/</guid>
      <description>We’ve designed Ergo with long-term economic sustainability in mind, and storage rent is one of the ways we’re ensuring miners stay profitable well into the future. One community member, Robert, describes this function as ‘on-chain garbage collection’ that reduces the problem of blockchain bloat – and even makes it profitable.
The 2020 block reward reduction will probably be the most important halving Bitcoin ever experiences. This is the point where the narrative of programmatic scarcity and digital gold will truly be proven, in the context of the sharpest economic downturn in living memory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ergo use case: Local Exchange Trading System (LETS)</title>
      <link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_02_use_cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_02_use_cases/</guid>
      <description>The need to reform the global financial system has been clear since the last crisis in 2008. Now, COVID-19 has forced our hands. We cannot delay, and the best way to start is from the grassroots.
As lockdowns across the world effectively shut down whole sectors and a large part of the economy, we are entering a new era at breakneck pace. Central banks are taking unprecedented action in the form of money printing but, just like last time around, they will almost certainly fail at the ‘last mile’ (intentionally or otherwise): while their efforts will benefit the financial sector and the wealthy, the funds will not reach those small businesses and individuals who need them the most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ergo use case: ‘hot potato’ monetary policy</title>
      <link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_02_use_hot_potato/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_02_use_hot_potato/</guid>
      <description>As the next financial crisis takes hold, it’s clear that conventional monetary policy is at its limit. Smart contract platforms like Ergo enable more innovative, targeted implementations of economic stimulation that the conventional banking sector cannot achieve.
Conventional monetary policy is a hammer. It works as far as it goes, but if all you have is a hammer then every problem starts to look like a nail.
When the Global Financial Crisis hit over a decade ago, central banks did what they were used to doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Ergo: Sigma protocols</title>
      <link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_16_ergo_sigma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_16_ergo_sigma/</guid>
      <description>Ergo’s smart contracts and DeFi functionality are built on Sigma protocols – a powerful, flexible class of zero-knowledge proofs. Find out more about why they’re so important, and how they put Ergo head and shoulders above the competition.
Cryptography is a fascinating area, and one of the most exciting and intriguing concepts it offers are zero-knowledge proofs. In simple terms, a zero-knowledge proof allows someone to prove they know the solution to a problem without actually revealing the solution itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Ergo: UTXO vs Account</title>
      <link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_03_building_utxo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_03_building_utxo/</guid>
      <description>Ergo takes the most secure and best-established features of Bitcoin and implements advanced new cryptographic features on its rock-solid foundations. This series explores the choices we have made in creating Ergo, with the first article unpacking the advantages of the UTXO model.
When you’re dealing with financial value, you cannot afford to take chances. Every architecture decision in a cryptocurrency platform has implications. While there are different ways to solve the same problem, some solutions are better tested and more reliable than others.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>