<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Building Ergo on Ergo</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/tags/building-ergo/</link><description>Recent content in Building Ergo on Ergo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 18:59:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ergoplatform.org/en/tags/building-ergo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Multi-Stage Contracts</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2021-04-16-multi-stage-contracts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 18:59:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2021-04-16-multi-stage-contracts/</guid><description>Smart contracts are the backbone of decentralized finance. Through smart contracts, users can interact with dApps without middlemen. Blockchain design has a significant impact on the capabilities of smart contracts. Ergo Blockchain’s UTXO model allows multi-stage contracts to operate on a highly scalable network. Decentralized Finance The banking system is built solely on trust. However, this trust mechanism is a form of obligation that citizens don’t have any choice on. Banks and financial institutions produce and provide financial products such as loans or ETFs to financial markets.</description></item><item><title>Here’s how Ergo seeks to boost interoperability for Cardano’s eUTxO model</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2021-04-08-heres-how-ergo-seeks-to-boost-interoperability-for-cardanos-eutxo-model/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 06:42:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2021-04-08-heres-how-ergo-seeks-to-boost-interoperability-for-cardanos-eutxo-model/</guid><description>Blockchain interoperability refers to the ability of different blockchain protocols to become compatible with one another. Achieving true blockchain interoperability among heterogeneous protocols is a prerequisite step for mainstream adoption of blockchain technology. This is true because many businesses are reluctant to build within a locked platform environment.
In this article, we are going to look at how Ergo platform will help in the interoperability of Cardano.
Bitcoin’s flawed UTXO Model The UTXO model has been in cryptocurrency since the conception of Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>ErgoDEX Model - AMM and Order Book Type Exchange</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2021-04-06-ergodex-model-amm-and-order-book-type-exchange/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 09:05:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2021-04-06-ergodex-model-amm-and-order-book-type-exchange/</guid><description>Trustless Exchange models vary in their use cases e.g AMMs for low liquidity pairs and Order Books for high liquidity pairs. But you don’t have to choose anymore because ErgoDEX can bring both - and with partial filling support!
Decentralized Exchanges AMMs(Automated Market Maker) is a type of market making algorithm, used in Decentralized Exchanges (DEXs) which allows participants to add liquidity in pairs and earn yields from transactions. AMM type DEXs have seen tremendous growth in recent months.</description></item><item><title>SigmaUSD - Ergo’s Community Deployed Stablecoin Is Live!</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2021_02_26-sigmausd-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2021_02_26-sigmausd-released/</guid><description>The SigmaUSD stablecoin has been deployed by the community and is live and ready for all Ergonauts to use at https://sigmausd.io/
After several months of hearing whispers about a stablecoin being built and teasers being thrown around, the Ergo community enjoyed an information-packed Ergo Summit 2021 which explained everything they needed to know about the AgeUSD Protocol; a novel crypto-backed algorithmic stablecoin protocol that has been created in joint partnership by the Ergo Foundation, EMURGO, and IOG on top of the Ergo Blockchain.</description></item><item><title>2000 ERG in Prizes to be Won in the Ergo Digital Art Competition!</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2021-02-12-2000-erg-in-prizes-to-be-won-in-the-ergo-digital-art-competition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 19:17:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2021-02-12-2000-erg-in-prizes-to-be-won-in-the-ergo-digital-art-competition/</guid><description>Create an original piece of digital art and list it for sale on the Ergo NFT Marketplace. The winning entry will receive 1000 ERG, with two further prizes of 500 ERG.
Digital art and NFTs are hot trends in the blockchain space, and Ergo has pioneered new approaches to minting NFTs. To celebrate the digital art sector and raise awareness of Ergo’s capabilities, we’re holding a digital art competition.
The competition will include three categories:</description></item><item><title>Building Ergo: How the AgeUSD stablecoin works</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2021-02-05-building-ergo-how-the-ageusd-stablecoin-works/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 11:54:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2021-02-05-building-ergo-how-the-ageusd-stablecoin-works/</guid><description>The elegant design avoids some of the complexity and potential problems of other approaches to creating decentralised, collateralised stablecoins.
As part of an ongoing joint initiative, Ergo and Cardano unveiled the design of a new stablecoin at the online Ergo Summit event, held on 23 January.
Named AgeUSD and inspired by StatiCoin, the stablecoin is the result of a collaboration between research and development teams across three organisations: IOG (IOHK), the company leading Cardano core development; Ergo Foundation; and blockchain technology company, Emurgo, also one of the founding members of Cardano.</description></item><item><title>How Ergo Makes the Most of Blockchain</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2021-01-20-how-ergo-makes-the-most-of-blockchain/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 14:16:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2021-01-20-how-ergo-makes-the-most-of-blockchain/</guid><description>The concept of ‘marginal gains’ enables Ergo to push the capacity of first-generation blockchain technology further than other platforms.
With the explosion of interest in DeFi, perhaps the most compelling use case for smart contract blockchain platforms, one thing has become abundantly clear: blockchain is not ready for DeFi.
DeFi dApps have overloaded the Ethereum blockchain, causing long delays and soaring fees for transactions. Ethereum and many other platforms besides have researched and implemented fixes to address the lack of capacity.</description></item><item><title>What Ergo can contribute to DeFi interoperability</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2021-01-05-what-ergo-can-contribute-to-defi-interoperability/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 07:08:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2021-01-05-what-ergo-can-contribute-to-defi-interoperability/</guid><description>Most users won’t care about the underlying blockchain they’re using – they will just want its functionality. That means DeFi interoperability will be critical.
Despite the open source nature of the blockchain world, crypto projects have always tended to have an ‘us-and-them’ mentality. The assumption is that for one platform to succeed, it must be at the expense of all the others. Hence marketing strategies that position one or other platform as the ‘Ethereum killer’, and other such claims.</description></item><item><title>Introducing the Sigmaverse</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-12-27-introducing-the-sigmaverse/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 20:20:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-12-27-introducing-the-sigmaverse/</guid><description>Your portal to Ergo’s dApp universe is opening.
Ergo has some amazing tech and some talented developers. However, as a decentralised and community-powered platform, it’s not always easy to know what’s going on all the time. Different people are developing different dApps and use cases, formally and informally. Connecting them to the same users and building that all-important DeFi network effect isn’t always easy.
That’s what the Sigmaverse is about. Sigmaverse is a one-stop portal to the Ergo dApp ecosystem: a place where users can find all the cool functionality that community developers are building on Ergo, all in one place.</description></item><item><title>Ergo Bootstrap, Streamlining Ergo dApp Infrastructure With One Simple Tool</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-12-11-ergo-bootstrap-streamlining-ergo-dapp-infrastructure-with-one-simple-tool/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 09:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-12-11-ergo-bootstrap-streamlining-ergo-dapp-infrastructure-with-one-simple-tool/</guid><description>The Ergo ecosystem is quickly growing with new design patterns, tools, dApps, and more every single month. This is an exciting point in time for developers to jump in and get started.
That said, while building dApps on top of Ergo, vital infrastructure components to develop and run your dApp might be intimidating to set up for someone who is unfamiliar with the existing tooling. Between an Ergo full node, explorer back end, explorer front end, logging, and metrics, it can become quite overwhelming for a nascent dApp developer entering into the ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Ergo Headless dApp Framework Now Available</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-12-08-ergo-headless-dapp-framework-now-available/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 09:10:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-12-08-ergo-headless-dapp-framework-now-available/</guid><description>This new development will have a number of implications for the Ergo ecosystem and developers, making it far easier to build applications on Ergo.
In a recent article, we looked at the idea of ‘Headless’ dApps: portable dApp off-chain code that can be used by anyone to ship dApps easily by plugging different components together and adding an interface. On 30 November, a new release was made from the Emurgo code repository: the Ergo Headless dApp Framework (HDF)!</description></item><item><title>New Ergo Smart DEX Orders with buyback guarantees</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-12-02-new-ergo-smart-dex-orders-with-buyback-guarantees/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 18:43:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-12-02-new-ergo-smart-dex-orders-with-buyback-guarantees/</guid><description>The novel smart contract will trustlessly enable users to participate in token sales without the downside risks of regular ICOs.
2020 is shaping up to look at a lot like 2016 for crypto – suggesting that 2021 could be another 2017.
But while 2017’s epic crypto bull run was partially driven by the massive ICO hype, 2020’s has not been – and any continuing rally in 2021 will likewise not rely on these token sales.</description></item><item><title>Ergo Foundation Makes Key dApp Infrastructure Grant</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-11-18-ergo-foundation-makes-key-dapp-infrastructure-grant/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 20:28:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-11-18-ergo-foundation-makes-key-dapp-infrastructure-grant/</guid><description>The Ergo Foundation will consider proposals for grants towards projects that will support significant ecosystem developments.
Ergo is a community-oriented project, with many contributors to various aspects of the ecosystem. Grants are available from the Ergo Foundation to help fund this work, which is vital for building out the everyday products and services required by users, as well as more diverse DeFi applications. The Foundation is actively seeking to make new grants, and has just voted to accept a brand new proposal that will improve the experience for all dApp developers.</description></item><item><title>Introducing the ‘Ergonaut’: the Ergo Foundation NFT sale!</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-11-17-introducing-the-ergonaut-the-ergo-foundation-nft-sale/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 13:16:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-11-17-introducing-the-ergonaut-the-ergo-foundation-nft-sale/</guid><description>This major auction will help fund the dev work carried out by our anons, and offers the opportunity for anyone to get their hands on a piece of Ergo history, thanks to the updated Auction House working with any Ergo wallet!
The launch of Ergo’s Auction House was a great milestone for Ergo Platform. Ergo NFTs offer additional features to those on other blockchains, and our auction back in October sold the first ever PoW-backed NFT to raise funds for developers.</description></item><item><title>Magnum Wallet to be Suspended – Transfer Your ERG to Yoroi</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-11-11-magnum-wallet-to-be-suspended-transfer-your-erg-to-yoroi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 21:15:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-11-11-magnum-wallet-to-be-suspended-transfer-your-erg-to-yoroi/</guid><description>Magnum, a popular lite wallet for ERG and other currencies, will cease to operate at the end of the month.
Many of the Ergo community use Magnum, a lite multi-wallet that was one of the first solutions to provide support for ERG.
Unfortunately, Magnum will be suspended at the end of the month. The Magnum team recently posted in Telegram:
Dear users,
today we are forced to inform you that in 20 days Magnum Wallet will be suspended.</description></item><item><title>First steps towards interoperability with Cardano oracles</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-11-09-first-steps-towards-interoperability-with-cardano-oracles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 18:01:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-11-09-first-steps-towards-interoperability-with-cardano-oracles/</guid><description>The oracle solution for Cardano will post data from Ergo’s oracle pools, treating the pre-processed data as a trusted source for its own records to the blockchain.
Back at the end of August, we announced Oracle Pools: a new approach to oracles, powered by Ergo’s extended-UTXO model. The benefits of these oracles over existing models are considerable, and they allow the creation of new types of dApp.
Now, one of Cardano’s oracles is using data provided by Ergo’s oracle pools.</description></item><item><title>The US Election and Blockchain: the Risk of Hard Forks</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-11-03-the-us-election-and-blockchain-the-risk-of-hard-forks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 07:08:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-11-03-the-us-election-and-blockchain-the-risk-of-hard-forks/</guid><description>What happens in an election has many parallels to the governance of blockchain platforms. Ergo, though, has a better way to deal with differences and the need to make changes to the system.
Tuesday, 3 November 2020, brings the most hotly-anticipated election in living memory. The background needs no explanation. Both Republicans and Democrats see their way of life threatened. The stakes could barely be higher.
Whatever the polls say, there is only one vote that ultimately matters.</description></item><item><title>The First Ergo NFT Auction Is Under Way!</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-10-19-the-first-ergo-nft-auction-is-under-way/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 14:34:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-10-19-the-first-ergo-nft-auction-is-under-way/</guid><description>The first ever PoW-backed NFT was generated by Ergo developer anon_real, and is being sold to help fund creation of the new Ergo DEX.
Ergo recently announced two major new developments: the ability to create non-fungible tokens, and the Ergo Auction House, a Marketplace for NFTs.
The very first Ergo NFT is now for sale on Auction House.
This is a unique, indivisible token mined by anon_real, one of Ergo’s anonymous devs.</description></item><item><title>Announcing the Auction House, NFT Marketplace on Ergo</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-10-16-announcing-the-auction-house-nft-marketplace-on-ergo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 09:00:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-10-16-announcing-the-auction-house-nft-marketplace-on-ergo/</guid><description>The platform allows users to sell Ergo’s NFTs – an important development in the growing DeFi movement – securely and easily.
Non-fungible tokens, or NFTs, aren’t a new development, but with the rise of the DeFi space they are gaining significance and finding new use cases.
NFTs are indivisible unique or limited-edition tokens that can be used to represent physical or digital items: anything from a house or car to a piece of digital art, a series of images, an in-game item or other collectible.</description></item><item><title>Learn ErgoScript by Example</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-10-12-learn-ergoscript-by-example/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 08:14:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-10-12-learn-ergoscript-by-example/</guid><description>The new resources provide a powerful but simple way to learn UTXO-based smart contracts.
Since its mainnet launch in July 2019, Ergo has steadily been building out both its core tech and its dapps ecosystem, with several unique developments in both. Ergo’s Sigma Protocols enable safe, customisable zero-knowledge proofs, which underpin such applications as ErgoMixer and the ZKTreasury. And there’s lots more to come!
To date, though, Ergo hasn’t been the most user-friendly ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>What will DeFi look like in 10 years?</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-10-04-what-will-defi-look-like-in-10-years/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 17:13:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-10-04-what-will-defi-look-like-in-10-years/</guid><description>This is the first in a series of articles speculating on how the fast-emerging DeFi sector might evolve in the coming years.
The DeFi movement as it currently exists is only a few months old, and blockchain itself has barely existed a decade. Already, though, we are beginning to see themes crystallising and the first popular use cases becoming established.
As a DeFi platform that takes positioning for the future seriously, it’s important that Ergo has a vision – not only a sense of where things might be heading, but the role that it should itself be playing as these new decentralised financial services consolidate and grow in popularity.</description></item><item><title>NFTs on Ergo</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-09-25-nfts-on-ergo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 05:58:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-09-25-nfts-on-ergo/</guid><description>As with almost every other area of DeFi, Ergo Platform takes a different approach to NFTs that offers some interesting and unique use cases and benefits.
NFTs look set to become the next major frontier for blockchain. Over the course of this year, crypto has become an accepted and practically mainstream (if still new) means of hedging against inflation and storing value. The emergence of DeFi as a use case for blockchain has similarly been impressive over the past few months, regardless of the issues that still need to be solved.</description></item><item><title>DeFi: Finance, but not always Decentralised?</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-09-17-defi-finance-but-not-always-decentralised/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 19:04:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-09-17-defi-finance-but-not-always-decentralised/</guid><description>As a recent blog post explored, DeFi – decentralised finance – can and will be used in whatever ways developers and the market see fit. This is the nature of open, decentralised systems. You can’t stop it, and there’s a very strong argument for saying we shouldn’t try. To restrict any element of DeFi, at least at the protocol level, is to introduce centralisation and single points of failure, thereby killing the core innovation by misguidedly trying to protect it.</description></item><item><title>Announcing the ZK Treasury on Ergo!</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-09-04-announcing-the-zk-treasury-on-ergo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 18:54:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-09-04-announcing-the-zk-treasury-on-ergo/</guid><description>Ergo’s Zero-Knowledge Treasury enables users to easily create joint digital signatures, with bespoke conditions for spending funds, while ensuring the signatories to the created address remain hidden.
Zero-Knowledge (ZK) cryptography offers lots of powerful use cases. The benefit of ZK operations is that not only are they secure, but they’re private.
Imagine you find a smartphone on the ground in the park. A woman close by claims it’s hers, but you don’t trust her.</description></item><item><title>Some thoughts about DeFi, Yield Farming and how open systems ‘should’ be used</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-09-03-some-thoughts-about-defi-yield-farming-and-how-open-systems-should-be-used/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 08:34:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-09-03-some-thoughts-about-defi-yield-farming-and-how-open-systems-should-be-used/</guid><description>At the risk of stating the obvious, decentralisation is the hallmark of DeFi. It is decentralisation that brings the benefits of transparency, accessibility, security, immutability, composability, efficiency and more besides to these new financial initiatives.
As a DeFi platform that aims to take and build on the best features of Bitcoin, Ergo is committed to decentralisation.
And so it is with a mixture of interest, concern, excitement, dismay and, frankly, awe that we watch the current DeFi craze for Yield Farming unfold.</description></item><item><title>Ergo’s Oracle Pools, and what they mean for the ecosystem</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-08-31-ergos-oracle-pools-and-what-they-mean-for-the-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 09:31:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-08-31-ergos-oracle-pools-and-what-they-mean-for-the-ecosystem/</guid><description>The new scheme developed through the Emurgo-Ergo partnership will see oracle pools – core blockchain infrastructure – run as a public service, accessible by any dApp and developer, free at the point of use.
Oracles are a crucial element of DeFi infrastructure. They are the bridge between the siloed world of the blockchain and data from the real world, and so are vital for DeFi to reach its full potential. The integrity of major use cases, including stablecoins and lending platforms, rely on oracles that are fit for purpose.</description></item><item><title>The Evolution of Programmable Money</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-08-20-the-evolution-of-programmable-money/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 20:17:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-08-20-the-evolution-of-programmable-money/</guid><description>Ergo is building the most effective programmable currency in history.
Money is changing. It’s interesting that, at a time when money is increasingly being trivialised and devalued through enormous quantitative easing, evolution and innovation in a parallel sphere is qualitatively improving money. One of the key ways in which blockchain is enhancing money is programmability.
Money is just information. Once that basic principle has been accepted, it opens a whole new arena and value proposition for cash.</description></item><item><title>Ergo’s Vision for DeFi: Ergo vs CBDCs</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-08-17-ergos-vision-for-defi-ergo-vs-cbdcs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 18:44:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-08-17-ergos-vision-for-defi-ergo-vs-cbdcs/</guid><description>As blockchain technology gains traction, central bank digital currencies are among the most significant applications being developed. But these will inevitably fall far short of the ideal, for one simple reason: control. In particular, that has implications for composability and privacy, and much else besides.
Central bank digital currencies are no longer a theoretical application of blockchain technology. The list of countries developing CBDCs is growing rapidly, with several now trialing state-backed digital cash.</description></item><item><title>Building Ergo: Our Vision for DeFi</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-08-13-building-ergo-our-vision-for-defi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 19:27:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-08-13-building-ergo-our-vision-for-defi/</guid><description>Everyone is talking about DeFi. Few people are asking what DeFi should look like. Ergo has a vision for what the sector can become.
2020 is shaping up to be the year in which Decentralised Finance rose to mainstream attention, in the same way that Bitcoin and blockchain did in 2016 and 2017. In July alone, Total Value Locked – the amount of funds committed to DeFi dApps’ smart contracts – doubled from $2 billion to $4 billion, largely driven by Compound’s distribution of its COMP governance tokens.</description></item><item><title>Decentralized Exchange Contracts on Ergo</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-07-31-decentralized-exchange-contracts-on-ergo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 09:46:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-07-31-decentralized-exchange-contracts-on-ergo/</guid><description>Ergo has expressive smart contracts and transactional model which allows for an implementation of trustless DEX protocol, in which signed buy and sell orders can be put into the blockchain independently by buyers and sellers. An off-chain matching service can observe the Ergo blockchain, find matching orders, and submit the swap transaction without knowing any secrets. The matching can be incentivized by DEX reward paid as part of a swap transaction.</description></item><item><title>Ergo Foundation - New members and contests</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-07-27-ergo-foundation-new-members-and-contests/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 20:21:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-07-27-ergo-foundation-new-members-and-contests/</guid><description>Ergo Foundation, a community-driven entity, is welcoming its new member Robert Kornacki, head of research and development engineer at EMURGO https://emurgo.io. This addition will help with the development of the ecosystem, promotion, and the widespread adoption and use of the Ergo Platform and its native token (ERG). There are many more members nominated to join the foundation, everyone is also free to apply.
Ergo Foundation would like to announce two sponsored competitions: for open-source mining software, including optimizations for both Nvidia and AMD which should fit greatly incoming HF changes and enable better competition in case of the new POW algorithm in the cryptocurrency space.</description></item><item><title>Building Ergo: Lite full nodes</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_05_08_lite_full_nodes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_05_08_lite_full_nodes/</guid><description>Ergo allows any user to run a full node with low resources – meaning you can help maintain the network with a device as simple as a Raspberry Pi.
In a previous post, we looked at Ergo’s SPV mode, which allows for secure, efficient mobile clients. This enables users to make transactions using almost any device.
At the other end of the scale, you might want to run a full node.</description></item><item><title>Building Ergo: SPV security</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_05_1_spv_security/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_05_1_spv_security/</guid><description>There’s often a tension in the crypto world between security and convenience. That trade-off is unacceptable if we want these technologies to be widely used. Here’s how Ergo addresses one common and very important issue.
We all know that the most secure way to use Bitcoin, or any crypto, is to download a copy of the blockchain and run a full node yourself. That way, every time you or anyone else makes a transaction, your client checks the blockchain to ensure it’s valid.</description></item><item><title>Building Ergo: Atomic Swaps</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_24_atomic_swaps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_24_atomic_swaps/</guid><description>Because a blockchain is a siloed, self-contained system by design, interacting with other blockchain protocols is challenging. Atomic Swaps enable cross-chain exchange of digital assets, avoiding the need for centralised exchanges.
Blockchains are excellent at decentralised value transfer within their own domains. That is, you can send BTC to any Bitcoin address securely and easily, and you can send LTC to any Litecoin address securely and easily too.
But because blockchains are based on consensus between miners, they are not designed to interface with other blockchains.</description></item><item><title>Building Ergo: Oracles</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_04_building_ergo_oracles/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_04_building_ergo_oracles/</guid><description>Blockchains are siloed systems that can only reference their own data, established by consensus. Oracles are the solution to the problem of working with external information, which is vital for many everyday use cases.
Blockchains are intentionally self-contained. They reference information only recorded within their immediate ecosystem, that has been agreed upon by a majority of miners. Since the whole point of a blockchain, based on consensus, is that there are no sources of centralisation or single points of failure, that poses a problem.</description></item><item><title>Building Ergo: Storage rent</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_21_ergo_positioning/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_21_ergo_positioning/</guid><description>We’ve designed Ergo with long-term economic sustainability in mind, and storage rent is one of the ways we’re ensuring miners stay profitable well into the future. One community member, Robert, describes this function as ‘on-chain garbage collection’ that reduces the problem of blockchain bloat – and even makes it profitable.
The 2020 block reward reduction will probably be the most important halving Bitcoin ever experiences. This is the point where the narrative of programmatic scarcity and digital gold will truly be proven, in the context of the sharpest economic downturn in living memory.</description></item><item><title>Ergo use case: Local Exchange Trading System (LETS)</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_02_use_cases/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_02_use_cases/</guid><description>The need to reform the global financial system has been clear since the last crisis in 2008. Now, COVID-19 has forced our hands. We cannot delay, and the best way to start is from the grassroots.
As lockdowns across the world effectively shut down whole sectors and a large part of the economy, we are entering a new era at breakneck pace. Central banks are taking unprecedented action in the form of money printing but, just like last time around, they will almost certainly fail at the ‘last mile’ (intentionally or otherwise): while their efforts will benefit the financial sector and the wealthy, the funds will not reach those small businesses and individuals who need them the most.</description></item><item><title>Ergo use case: ‘hot potato’ monetary policy</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_02_use_hot_potato/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_02_use_hot_potato/</guid><description>As the next financial crisis takes hold, it’s clear that conventional monetary policy is at its limit. Smart contract platforms like Ergo enable more innovative, targeted implementations of economic stimulation that the conventional banking sector cannot achieve.
Conventional monetary policy is a hammer. It works as far as it goes, but if all you have is a hammer then every problem starts to look like a nail.
When the Global Financial Crisis hit over a decade ago, central banks did what they were used to doing.</description></item><item><title>Building Ergo: Sigma protocols</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_16_ergo_sigma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_16_ergo_sigma/</guid><description>Ergo’s smart contracts and DeFi functionality are built on Sigma protocols – a powerful, flexible class of zero-knowledge proofs. Find out more about why they’re so important, and how they put Ergo head and shoulders above the competition.
Cryptography is a fascinating area, and one of the most exciting and intriguing concepts it offers are zero-knowledge proofs. In simple terms, a zero-knowledge proof allows someone to prove they know the solution to a problem without actually revealing the solution itself.</description></item><item><title>Building Ergo: UTXO vs Account</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_03_building_utxo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_03_building_utxo/</guid><description>Ergo takes the most secure and best-established features of Bitcoin and implements advanced new cryptographic features on its rock-solid foundations. This series explores the choices we have made in creating Ergo, with the first article unpacking the advantages of the UTXO model.
When you’re dealing with financial value, you cannot afford to take chances. Every architecture decision in a cryptocurrency platform has implications. While there are different ways to solve the same problem, some solutions are better tested and more reliable than others.</description></item></channel></rss>