<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Roadmap on Ergo</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/tags/roadmap/</link><description>Recent content in Roadmap on Ergo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 10:20:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ergoplatform.org/en/tags/roadmap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title> 2021: The Next Battlegrounds for DeFi</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-12-18-2021-the-next-battlegrounds-for-defi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 10:20:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-12-18-2021-the-next-battlegrounds-for-defi/</guid><description>The challenge for Ergo and all DeFi platforms over the next year is to work towards the complete set of features that will enable DeFi to take on the conventional financial sector: decentralised atomic composability at scale with opt-in auditable privacy.
As 2020 draws to a close, it’s worth looking back at what has been a landmark year for crypto and DeFi.
Since the COVID-induced global market turbulence of March, we have seen crypto establish itself as an asset class as corporate investors began buying bitcoin as a store of value and a hedge against dollar devaluation in the wake of unprecedented money printing.</description></item><item><title>Yoroi: your gateway to Ergo dapps</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-10-09-yoroi-your-gateway-to-ergo-dapps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 13:44:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-10-09-yoroi-your-gateway-to-ergo-dapps/</guid><description>Yoroi, the flagship lite wallet app for the Cardano ecosystem developed by Emurgo, now supports Ergo! This development follows directly from the Ergo-Emurgo partnership announced in June this year.
https://twitter.com/YoroiWallet/status/1314244618435739648
At present, Yoroi functions as a multi-wallet for ADA and ERG tokens, enabling secure storage and transaction of your crypto.
In the coming months the Ergo integration within Yoroi will be developed further. Yoroi will become the gateway to Ergo’s ecosystem of Sigma Protocol-powered dApps.</description></item><item><title>Ergo roadmap for 2020</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-08-04-ergo-roadmap-for-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 14:02:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-08-04-ergo-roadmap-for-2020/</guid><description>Future dates at time of publication are subject to change
March 2020: Command-line version of decentralised trustless mixer, ErgoMixer, launched
April 2020: Command-line version of decentralised exchange
April 2020: ErgoMixer with Web interface (simple PoC)
June 2020: Ergo and Emurgo announce joint research partnership, including integration of Ergo into Emurgo’s flagship Yoroi wallet
June 2020: ErgoMixer with GUI
June 2020: New Emurgo brand, Emurgo Research, releases first research report on UTXO-based contracts.</description></item><item><title>Ergo Platform Roadmap for 2020</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_02_02/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_02_02/</guid><description>Ergo community made a lot in 2019: Very stressful but successful mainnet launch A lot of updates for Ergo protocol reference client to improve its stability and enhance functionality. Wallets: Magnum, CoinBarn (coming to ChromeStore, binaries available), UI panel in the node First applications, in form of command-line scripts, so not for regular users yet: a tool for crowdfunding campaigns, Ergo Notary, Ergo Oracle. Few Ergo improvement proposals, already implemented!</description></item></channel></rss>