<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ergo Team on Ergo</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/tags/ergo-team/</link><description>Recent content in Ergo Team on Ergo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 18:59:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ergoplatform.org/en/tags/ergo-team/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Transcript of the Oracle Pools Q&amp;A session with Robert Kornacki</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-08-28-transcript-of-first-q-a-session-with-robert-kornacki/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 18:59:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020-08-28-transcript-of-first-q-a-session-with-robert-kornacki/</guid><description>Robert Kornacki
I&amp;rsquo;d like to officially announce that Oracle Pools are live, running on mainnet, with all the code + detailed instructions available for you to start/run your own, and we have a beautiful frontend created by DeadIT now implemented in the explorer https://explorer.ergoplatform.com/en/oracle-pools-list
Can Ergo Oracle Pools be used on Eth projects?
A similar system could be developed &amp;amp; deployed on Eth, but all the data is posted on the Ergo blockchain so available to all Ergo users.</description></item><item><title>Ergo-Emurgo partnership yields new model for oracles</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_06_30_ergo_emurgo_oracles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_06_30_ergo_emurgo_oracles/</guid><description>The joint research on oracle pools will be implemented in the Ergo stablecoin project.
Oracles are one of the critical elements of DeFi, providing a link between the siloed and self-contained world of the blockchain, and real-world data. It is imperative that dApps have access to reliable price data, among other information, in order to execute effectively and securely.
New research from the Ergo-Emurgo partnership offers a new way to approach the problem of achieving consensus and posting data to the blockchain: Oracle Pools.</description></item><item><title>The opportunities of the Ergo/Emurgo partnership</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_06_11_emurgo_ergo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_06_11_emurgo_ergo/</guid><description>Cardano and Ergo take quite different approaches to DeFi and blockchain development, but there are specific areas in which they significantly overlap. This allows the possibility of fruitful collaboration, with benefits to two distinct ecosystems – and the blockchain space as a whole.
The recent partnership announced between Emurgo and Ergo has been positively received by both communities. For good reason: this is an exceptional opportunity to pool resources into an important and emerging area of research, while allowing both projects to use the insights gained in their own ways and for their own roadmaps.</description></item><item><title>Press release: Ergo Foundation partners with Emurgo to research and develop new DeFi solutions</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_06_09_press_release/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_06_09_press_release/</guid><description>The collaboration will encompass a range of objectives – including exploration of a decentralised stablecoin solution.
Ergo, the smart contracts platform designed by former IOHK engineers, and Emurgo, a global blockchain solutions firm and one of the founding entities of Cardano, have entered into a partnership with the aim of furthering the DeFi space with ambitious new research and technology.
Research-driven technology Both Ergo and Emurgo have a reputation for taking an academically-rigorous approach to development, basing their technology on peer-reviewed research by top cryptographers and blockchain specialists.</description></item><item><title>Ergo update, 14 May 2020: New exchange, wallet and first mining pool with collaterals!</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_05_14_updates/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_05_14_updates/</guid><description>We have three great new developments to announce to the Ergo community, all of which will boost our user base and decentralisation!
We have not just one but three outstanding developments for the Ergo ecosystem to announce! Together, these will make it easier than ever before to acquire, trade, store and spend ERG – and will open up a huge new potential community of users, developers and hodlers.
Coinsbit listing and airdrop Firstly, ERG has been listed on Coinsbit: a major trading platform that enables fiat deposits and withdrawals via debit and credit card.</description></item><item><title>Ergo use case: Local Exchange Trading System (LETS)</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_02_use_cases/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_04_02_use_cases/</guid><description>The need to reform the global financial system has been clear since the last crisis in 2008. Now, COVID-19 has forced our hands. We cannot delay, and the best way to start is from the grassroots.
As lockdowns across the world effectively shut down whole sectors and a large part of the economy, we are entering a new era at breakneck pace. Central banks are taking unprecedented action in the form of money printing but, just like last time around, they will almost certainly fail at the ‘last mile’ (intentionally or otherwise): while their efforts will benefit the financial sector and the wealthy, the funds will not reach those small businesses and individuals who need them the most.</description></item><item><title>Ergo use cases: safe, simple financial contracts</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_29_ergo_use/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_29_ergo_use/</guid><description>Ergo enables new models of financial interaction, underpinned by smart contracts built on flexible and powerful Sigma protocols but easily accessible to developers.
One of the most exciting things about blockchain is the possibility of making digital agreements without any trusted intermediaries. In the simplest use case, pioneered by Bitcoin, Alice can send a payment directly to Bob, wherever the two of them are located around the world, with no bank or any trusted third party needed.</description></item><item><title>Building Ergo: Sigma protocols</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_16_ergo_sigma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_16_ergo_sigma/</guid><description>Ergo’s smart contracts and DeFi functionality are built on Sigma protocols – a powerful, flexible class of zero-knowledge proofs. Find out more about why they’re so important, and how they put Ergo head and shoulders above the competition.
Cryptography is a fascinating area, and one of the most exciting and intriguing concepts it offers are zero-knowledge proofs. In simple terms, a zero-knowledge proof allows someone to prove they know the solution to a problem without actually revealing the solution itself.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Σ3 – ErgoMixer</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_20_ergo_mixer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_20_ergo_mixer/</guid><description>The project uses Ergo’s Sigma protocols to enable efficient, trustless mixing of funds, enabling a high degree of privacy while ensuring security is not compromised.
ErgoMixer command-line demo tool along with detailed technical description can be found at https://github.com/anon92048/ergo-mixer-demo .
Ergo’s Sigma protocols can be used to create many interesting and exciting DeFi use cases, with greater simplicity, efficiency and security than other smart contract platforms offer. Created by one of Ergo’s community members @anon92408, Σ3 (‘Sigma Three’) is a powerful mixer that works by pooling funds and enabling participants to spend them without anyone knowing who made the transactions.</description></item><item><title>Building Ergo: UTXO vs Account</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_03_building_utxo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_03_building_utxo/</guid><description>Ergo takes the most secure and best-established features of Bitcoin and implements advanced new cryptographic features on its rock-solid foundations. This series explores the choices we have made in creating Ergo, with the first article unpacking the advantages of the UTXO model.
When you’re dealing with financial value, you cannot afford to take chances. Every architecture decision in a cryptocurrency platform has implications. While there are different ways to solve the same problem, some solutions are better tested and more reliable than others.</description></item><item><title>Ergo Platform Ecosystem Digest - February 2020</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_03_digest/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_03_03_digest/</guid><description>Ergo Platform Roadmap for 2020 has been released, the plan is minimum and very realistic https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_02_02/
Miners tested raising computational cost limit per block via voting with success
&amp;ldquo;Bypassing Non-Outsourceable Proof-of-Work Schemes Using Collateralized Smart Contracts&amp;rdquo; https://ia.cr/2020/044 was presented by Alex Chepurnoy at WTSC workshop associated with Financial Cryptography and Data Security 2020 in Malaysia
Few AMA sessions have been held with the Ergo team by Probit, ViteXExchange, and CryptoDaku.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to Smart Money</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_02_12_welcome_to_smart_money/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_02_12_welcome_to_smart_money/</guid><description>It’s the smartest crypto you’ve never heard of. Ergo takes the best of Bitcoin and integrates Sigma protocols so powerful they make Ethereum look like it would lose a game of chess against your cat. If you’re tired of spin and hype over solid tech, Ergo will remind you that in crypto, it’s always been fashionable to be intelligent. Bright is the new black, people, and Ergo is set to dazzle you.</description></item><item><title>Ergo Platform Ecosystem Digest - January 2020</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_02_04_january_digest/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_02_04_january_digest/</guid><description>Ergo Foundation has been established (https://ergoplatform.org/en/foundation/)
Security audit of most critical parts of the reference protocol client is done, report is available (https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_01_12_security_audit/)
New paper is out, &amp;ldquo;Bypassing Non-Outsourceable Proof-of-Work Schemes Using Collateralized Smart Contracts&amp;rdquo; (https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/044.pdf). This paper describes how to build a pool for Ergo based on smart contracts with collaterals.
Public Discord server has been created (https://discordapp.com/invite/gYrVrjS), please join!
Ergo Platform reference protocol client 3.</description></item><item><title>Ergo Platform Roadmap for 2020</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_02_02/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_02_02/</guid><description>Ergo community made a lot in 2019: Very stressful but successful mainnet launch A lot of updates for Ergo protocol reference client to improve its stability and enhance functionality. Wallets: Magnum, CoinBarn (coming to ChromeStore, binaries available), UI panel in the node First applications, in form of command-line scripts, so not for regular users yet: a tool for crowdfunding campaigns, Ergo Notary, Ergo Oracle. Few Ergo improvement proposals, already implemented!</description></item><item><title>Security Audit (by Jean Philippe Aumasson)</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_01_12_security_audit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2020_01_12_security_audit/</guid><description>We would like to announce that Ergo has successfully passed security audit of certain (most critical) parts of the code. This time the audit was done by Jean-Philipee Aumasson (aka veorq, https://aumasson.jp/ ).
The detailed report is below. Nothing critical is found. Comments on issues found:
On wallet password, we&amp;rsquo;ll provide a recommendation in next versions of the protocol client. Not sure hard enforcement on password will take place, but we&amp;rsquo;ll do more consultations on this.</description></item><item><title>Mining Ergo for Fun and Profit</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_12_22_mining_for_fun/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_12_22_mining_for_fun/</guid><description>Ergo GPU Mining This article will help you start mining Ergo using a GPU.
Ergo mining is based on Autolykos, a Proof-of-Work algorithm designed to be ASIC and pool resistant. Miners have to perform memory-hard computations~(at least 4 GB memory is needed, but the current most efficient implementation utilizes between 8 GB of vRAM) that makes Ergo friendly for GPU mining. In addition, Autolykos requires access to private keys, thereby preventing mining pool formation.</description></item><item><title>How to set up and configure a full Ergo node</title><link>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_12_02_how_to_setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ergoplatform.org/en/blog/2019_12_02_how_to_setup/</guid><description>This tutorial explains how to install and run a full Ergo node. It does not cover mining.
Node security There are a few important aspects of node usage that your wallet and money&amp;rsquo;s safety depends on:
An Ergo node requires storing security-critical parameters in the configuration file. You should never make this file public. An Ergo node provides a REST API for interacting with the built-in wallet. Sensitive API methods require a security token, which should never be sent over untrusted channels.</description></item></channel></rss>