<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on </title>
    <link>https://powerful-spire-67290.herokuapp.com/en/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 13:49:52 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://powerful-spire-67290.herokuapp.com/en/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Local Exchange Trading System On Top Of Ergo</title>
      <link>https://powerful-spire-67290.herokuapp.com/en/blog/2019_04_22-lets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://powerful-spire-67290.herokuapp.com/en/blog/2019_04_22-lets/</guid>
      <description>A local exchange trading system (LETS) is a local mutual credit association which members are allowed to create common credit money individually, with all the deals in the system written into a common ledger. As an example, assume that Alice with zero balance is willing to buy a liter of raw milk from Bob. First, they agree on a price, for example, assume that the price is about 2 Euro (as Alice and Bob are living in Ireland).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An ICO Example On Top Of Ergo</title>
      <link>https://powerful-spire-67290.herokuapp.com/en/blog/2019_04_10-ico-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://powerful-spire-67290.herokuapp.com/en/blog/2019_04_10-ico-example/</guid>
      <description>This article describes a full featured ICO (Initial Coin Offering) implemented in ErgoScript. The example covers several important and novel features of the Ergo Platform and shows how it can support complex contracts with tiny amount of code.
Part 1. Preliminaries An important design decision in a cryptocurrency protocol is specifying what a spending transaction actually spends. There are two possibilities here. The first a UTXO-based model, as in Bitcoin, where a transaction spends one-time asset containers (called as &amp;lsquo;coins&amp;rsquo; or UTXOs in Bitcoin) and creates new ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q&amp;A with Alex Chepurnoy and Dmitry Meshkov</title>
      <link>https://powerful-spire-67290.herokuapp.com/en/blog/2019_03_19-qa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://powerful-spire-67290.herokuapp.com/en/blog/2019_03_19-qa/</guid>
      <description>First, we have a major announcement - Ergo mainnet launch is planned for May 26 if no security vulnerabilities will be found during audit process!
What are the vision about scaling and adoption?
About scaling, the main approach is to avoid bloat without compromising functionality. E.g. persistent updateable storage is possible, with updates to be checked by a blockchain contract, but only digest of authenticated data structure (and some additional bytes, less than 40 bytes anyway) are stored in the UTXO set dependless on data set size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Contracts for the People</title>
      <link>https://powerful-spire-67290.herokuapp.com/en/blog/2018_10_19-smart-contracts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://powerful-spire-67290.herokuapp.com/en/blog/2018_10_19-smart-contracts/</guid>
      <description>!!! TODO !!!
A lot of blockchain-related news these days are saying us that a bank X or a corporation Y is going to use a “blockchain” to “reduce costs”. Basically it means that just another buzzword is considered by big banksters as just another tool to extract value from everywhere in a more efficient way, and also to save on cutting job positions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>